<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media Queries on FEWD</title>
    <link>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media Queries on FEWD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/15-responsive-design/media-queries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Query Overview</title>
      <link>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/media-query-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/media-query-overview/</guid>
      <description>What are the Media Queries?  Key element in responsive design
 Allow you to apply different styles based on the screen size of the user&amp;rsquo;s device (viewport)
 Media Queries ask questions such as: Is the width of the viewport greater than or equal to 768px?
 Media queries don’t affect the HTML (the actual content and structure of the underlying page) — they only affect the styles that are applied to the page using CSS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakpoints</title>
      <link>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>What are Breakpoints?  Term used to describe that specific widths (or points) where your CSS styles change as a result of a media queries   @media only screen and (min-width: 768px) { /* styles go here */ }  The example above, the styles inside the media query will go into effect at the point where the viewport width is greater than or equal to 768px
Example of CSS stylesheet with media queries  /* styles outside of the media queries are considered default styles */ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Breakpoints</title>
      <link>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/recommended-breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/15-responsive-design/media-queries/recommended-breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>If you are starting a responsive design project from scratch This approach assumes you are starting a responsive design project from scratch and you will use progressive enhancement (also referred to a &amp;ldquo;mobile first&amp;rdquo;) approach
/* main.css */ /* Extra small devices (portrait phones, less than 576px) No media query since styles outside of the media queries below will apply to everything &#39;up to 576px&#39; or everything below 576px */ p { } .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>